<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Bik Lab @ UC Riverside</title>
 <link href="biklab.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="biklab.github.io"/>
 <updated>2016-10-04T10:39:22-07:00</updated>
 <id>biklab.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Holly Bik</name>
   <email>holly.bik@ucr.edu</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Taruna Aggarwal</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/team/taruna-aggarwal"/>
   <updated>2016-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/team/taruna-aggarwal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Taruna recently completed her Master’s degree from the University of New Hampshire under the guidance of &lt;a href=&quot;http://genomebio.org/&quot;&gt;Matt MacManes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://broderslab.agsci.colostate.edu/&quot;&gt;Kirk Broders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Unravelling post-glacial colonization through molecular techniques: new insight from estuarine invertebrates</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/papers/paper/unravelling-post-glacial-colonization"/>
   <updated>2016-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/papers/paper/unravelling-post-glacial-colonization</id>
   <content type="html">
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rapid decline of PCR amplification from genomic extracts of DESS-preserved, slide-mounted nematodes</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/papers/paper/decline-of-pcr-amplification"/>
   <updated>2016-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/papers/paper/decline-of-pcr-amplification</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many studies use integrative methods to study both morphology and gene sequences of nematode species, yet there is little evidence to indicate the optimum criteria for merging taxonomic and molecular protocols. Preliminary evidence suggests that standard methods of desiccation and slide mounting nematode specimens in glycerin can sporadically result in degradation of genomic DNA. A time series experiment was constructed in order to assess whether this degradation of genomic DNA could be recorded and quantified. Two groups of nematode specimens were desiccated, mounted on slides, and stored at either 4°C or at room temperature for specified time intervals. Genomic DNA was extracted and PCR was conducted to amplify a section of the 18S rRNA gene at each time point. The resulting gel photographs were used to record the outcome of PCR and quantify the strength of amplification if successful. Results from slide-mounted specimens were compared to PCR products derived from unmounted nematodes extracted directly from the preservative solution at specified time intervals. The desiccation and slide mounting process appears to reduce overall band intensity after 1 day in slide mounts. Unmounted specimens consistently exhibit high success rates of PCR and a high overall DNA content per band at all time points, whereas slide-mounted nematodes show a decrease in the number of successful PCRs and weakening band intensity as time progresses. Results clearly indicate a steady degradation of genomic DNA in nematodes stored in slide mounts for more than 2 weeks, whereas unmounted specimens extracted from preservative solution showed no decline in PCR success or quality. We suggest a maximum storage period of 2 weeks on slides if mounted nematodes are to be used for molecular analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Join</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/misc/join-us"/>
   <updated>2016-10-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/misc/join-us</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;purpose&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-sites-inspirations&quot;&gt;Our site’s inspirations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Holly Bik</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/team/holly-bik"/>
   <updated>2016-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/team/holly-bik</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Insert Holly’s bio here.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Welcome to the Bik Lab</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/blog/welcome"/>
   <updated>2016-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/blog/welcome</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;!-- &gt; _Note: [Edward][1] sang the ditty below to us at his going-away party. He was the group's first postdoc, a scientist of tremendous range who trained as a mathematician and mastered [computational molecular evolution][2], then [experimental biochemistry][3], during his tenure. Now he's off to start his Marie Curie fellowship in Edinburgh. He is greatly admired, and already deeply missed. -- Allan_ --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our site in under construction so some links may not be functional yet.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A CBC Catalyst award to study asymmetric inheritance</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/news/catalyst-award"/>
   <updated>2016-04-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/news/catalyst-award</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.molbiosci.northwestern.edu/lackner/&quot;&gt;Laura Lackner&lt;/a&gt;’s group’ at Northwestern, we’ve just been awarded two years of collaborative funding to study how older cells retain stress-triggered aggregates by tethering aggregates to organelles. Thanks to the Chicago Biomedical Consortium, and the Searle Funds at The Chicago Community Trust, for this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicagobiomedicalconsortium.org/awards/catalyst_award/&quot;&gt;Catalyst award&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Disaggregation assay data visualization</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/data/postheat-disaggregation-yeast-visualization"/>
   <updated>2015-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/data/postheat-disaggregation-yeast-visualization</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interactive data visualization for disaggregation and new-synthesis data from &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/paper/endogenous-aggregates&quot;&gt;our 2015 paper on heat-triggered protein aggregation in yeast&lt;/a&gt;, Figure 6. (Aggregation data visualization is &lt;a href=&quot;/data/heat-aggregation-yeast-visualization&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose detected proteins by official yeast name, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeastgenome.org/&quot;&gt;SGD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cells were grown at 30°C, shifted to labeled media, heat-shocked for 10 minutes at 42°C, moved back to 30°C for recovery, and protein in 100,000g supernatant measured. Y-axis is ratio of protein in supernatant between treated and control cells, X-axis is either time or temperature of shock. Linetype reflects isotopic label on the amino acids: solid line is arginine/lysine imported before onset of heat shock, dashed line is imported after shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;https://dadrummond.shinyapps.io/ratiosup_shiny/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Aggregation assay data visualization</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/data/heat-aggregation-yeast-visualization"/>
   <updated>2015-07-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/data/heat-aggregation-yeast-visualization</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Interactive data visualization for data from &lt;a href=&quot;/papers/paper/endogenous-aggregates&quot;&gt;our 2015 paper on heat-triggered protein aggregation in yeast&lt;/a&gt;, Figure 1. (Disaggregation data visualization is &lt;a href=&quot;/data/postheat-disaggregation-yeast-visualization&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose detected proteins by official yeast name, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeastgenome.org/&quot;&gt;SGD&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y-axis is proportion of protein in 100,000g supernatant, X-axis is either time or temperature of shock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;720&quot; src=&quot;https://dadrummond.shinyapps.io/psup_shiny/&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bik Lab @ UC Riverside</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/misc/home/home"/>
   <updated>2015-04-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/misc/home/home</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We examine deep-sea microbiol eukaryotes and their structurally and functional composition in natural habitats.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chloroform-methanol extraction of proteins</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/protocols/protocol/chloroform-methanol-precipitation"/>
   <updated>2015-04-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/protocols/protocol/chloroform-methanol-precipitation</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Detergents, like SDS, and salts, like NaCl, can disrupt liquid chromatography/tandem mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS) studies by interfering with chemistry and clogging columns and spray needles. Precipitation with chloroform and methanol results in dry protein material, free of salt and detergent, which perform sweetly during these critical steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;protocol&quot;&gt;Protocol&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To 100 µL protein sample (~100ug protein) in a 1.5mL eppendorf tube:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 400 µL methanol and vortex thoroughly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 100 µL chloroform and vortex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 300 µL H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O—mixture will become cloudy with precipitate—and vortex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Centrifuge 1 minute @ 14,000g. Result is three layers: a large aqueous layer on top, a circular flake of protein in the interphase, and a smaller chloroform layer at the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove top aqueous layer carefully, trying not to disturb the protein flake.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add 400 µL methanol and vortex.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Centrifuge 5 minutes @ 20,000g, which will slam dandruffy precipitate against the tube wall.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove as much methanol as possible. Be careful, because the pellet is delicate. You should be able to remove all but a few µL of methanol with care, which will speed drying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dry under vacuum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adapted from Wessel, D. and Flügge, U.I. (1984) &lt;em&gt;Anal. Biochem.&lt;/em&gt; 138 141–143.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>About</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/misc/about"/>
   <updated>2015-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/misc/about</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;purpose&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;our-sites-inspirations&quot;&gt;Our site’s inspirations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our site is inspired by &lt;a href=&quot;http://bedford.io/team/trevor-bedford/&quot;&gt;Trevor Bedford&lt;/a&gt;’s and &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/team/d-allan-drummond&quot;&gt;D. Allan Drummond&lt;/a&gt;’s lab webpages. Our site is deployed using &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt; and the source code is available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BikLab/biklab.github.io&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Please feel free to use this code and reach out to us if you have any questions. Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;contact&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Regulation by massive molecular assembly</title>
   <link href="biklab.github.io/projects/project/stress-agg"/>
   <updated>2015-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>biklab.github.io/projects/project/stress-agg</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Stress triggers proteins to clump together into massive assemblies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;testing adding content&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
